JAMES WILLIAM SCHNEIDER

9 Harmony Street • Manorville, NY 11949 631-644-5641 • j.schneider@saeny.net

PROFILE

Entry Level Audio Engineer.

SAE Institute, Audio Technology Program Graduate with 4.0 GPA. Most expereince as a Recording Engineer and Mix Engineer through various consoles and interfaces. Live Sound experience with Theatre as Stage Crew and Church as Mix Engineer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Protools 8 LE/10/11/12
- Ableton
- Various Microphones
- Macintosh Computers
- Various Plug Ins

- Mackie 1604
- Logic Pro X
- Neve 88R
- Avid ICON
- Digidesign 002/003
- Presonus StudioLive 16.4.2AI
- SSL 4000 G+
- Yamaha 02R
- 5.1 Surround Mixing
- Audient 8024

WORK EXPERIENCE

Starbucks Riverhead, NY http://www.Starbucks.com **Barista**

2014-Present

Joes Crab Shack Riverhead, NY http://www.joescrabshack.com Server/Waiter/Bartender

Summer 2013

West Hampton Beach Performing Arts Center West Hampton, NY Stage Hand/Intern

2012

AUDIO ENGINEERING EXPERIENCE

SAE Institute New York City

2014-2016

(Student)

Hands-on audio technology teachings through consoles such as the Audient 8024, Yamaha 02R, Neve 88R, and SSL 4000 G+. Advanced understanding of audio software such as Protools, Logic Pro, and Ableton.

Living Water Full Gospel Church Riverhead, NY

2014

(Volunteering)

Mixing live performances and lectures through the operation of the Presonus 36.4.2 Ai.

EDUCATION

SAE Institute New York City Diploma, Audio Technology

2014-2016

Eastport South Manor Jr/Sr High School Manorville, NY Diploma, General

Certificate of Completion

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION ESBOCES Audio Production Honor Roll Year 2 Certificate Eastern Suffolk BOCES - Riverhead Campus ESBOCES Audio Production Honor Roll Year 1 Certificate Eastern Suffolk BOCES - Riverhead Campus AES Society Attendee Audio Engineering Society Consortium